Working Women Unite fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Working Women Unite fonds
1976 - 1982
F-45
Q100146310
25 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Working Women Unite
Working Women Unite was formed to create links between working women and the women's movement. The group focused on issues of women and work, and sought to create a relationship with trade unions that would further the position of women in the work force. Specifically, Working Women Unite sought to encourage the formation of women's committees within local unions, discuss strategies on how to organize in a non-union job, articulate feminist demands for working women to take to their unions when negotiating new contracts, and to recognize the value of all women's work regardless of whether it was paid or unpaid. The group also held conferences, workshops, and seminars on issues such as unpaid work, immigrant female workers, women in unions, women working in the home, equal pay for equal work, and the effects of video display terminals in the workplace.
Working Women Unite emerged from the British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW) during its convention in 1977. During this convention the lack of representation for working women within the BCFW was addressed by a group of women, primarily members of the Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC), who met and formulated resolutions that were passed at the convention. It was not until 1978 that the group gained momentum with a broader base of support. Women from unions such as the British Columbia Government Employees Union (BCGEU), Canadian Union of Postal Workers (CUPW), Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU), SORWUC, Letter Carriers Union of Canada (LCUC), and Canadian Union of Public Employees (CUPE), along with non-unionized women, and women in the home, became involved with the group. Structurally, Working Women Unite remained within the BCFW, a federation of women's groups in British Columbia working toward liberation of women through fundamental social change.
published
Full
Revised
Title is based on the provenance of the fonds.
Fonds consists of records created, received and collected by Working Women Unite. Records reflect the activities and functional responsibilities of Working Women Unite and groups associated with them, such as the BCFW and SORWUC. Includes correspondence, minutes, agendas, bulletins, newsletters, financial records, membership lists, reports, convention proceedings, and articles.
Original order was maintained by the Archivist where possible. Where no order was apparent, the materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Labour; Women
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Working Women Unite records, 1978 - 1982; F-45-1; 8 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to Working Women Unite. Includes financial records, correspondence, minutes, conference proceedings, articles, papers and bulletins.
  Working Women Unite
  - Working Women Unite - financial records, 1979 - 1982; F-45-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 45-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
  - Working Women Unite - notes and minutes, 1978 - 1981; F-45-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 45-1)
  - Working Women Unite - correspondence and bulletins, 1979 - 1981; F-45-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 45-1)
  - Working Women Unite - workshop on video display terminals and workplace health, 1980 - 1982; F-45-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 45-1)
  - Working Women Unite - Oct. 14, 1979 Conference, F-45-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 45-1)
    Open
  - Working Women Unite - articles and papers re: women and work, 1979 - 1980; F-45-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 45-1)
- British Columbia Federation of Women records, 1977 - 1982; F-45-2; 7 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the British Columbia Federation of Women (BCFW), the parent organization of Working Women Unite. Includes newsletters, draft convention proposals, minutes, agendas, constitution, policy handbooks, and proceedings of the 1979 and 1980 conventions.
  - British Columbia Federation of Women - minutes, 1978 - 1982; F-45-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 45-1)
  - British Columbia Federation of Women - policy records, 1977 - 1980; F-45-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 45-1)
  - British Columbia Federation of Women - newsletters, 1980 - 1982; F-45-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 45-1)
  - British Columbia Federation of Women - 1980 Convention, F-45-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 45-2)
  - British Columbia Federation of Women - 1979 Convention, F-45-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 45-2)
- Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada records, 1976 - 1982; F-45-3; 10 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC). Activities documented include policy development, fundraising, and conventions. Includes newsletters, bulletins, minutes of meetings, correspondence, copies of collective agreements negotiated by the union (with the Simon Fraser Student Society and the Pooh Corner Daycare), financial records, and convention proceedings.
  Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada
  - Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC) - newsletters and policy records, 1977 - 1982; F-45-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 45-2)
  - Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC) - minutes and membership lists, 1980 - 1982; F-45-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 45-2)
  - Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC) - fundraising records, 1980 - 1982; F-45-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 45-2)
  - Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC) - 1979 National Convention, 1978 - 1979; F-45-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 45-2)
  - Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC) - Local 1 executive minutes, 1978 - 1979; F-45-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 45-2)
  - Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC) - Local 1 1980 Convention, F-45-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 45-2)
  - Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC) - Local 1 1979 Convention, 1978 - 1979; F-45-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 45-2)
  - Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada (SORWUC) - Simon Fraser Student Society (SFSS) records, 1976 - 1982; F-45-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 45-2)